if if someone could give me it just
feels like panning for gold right it's
like if someone could give me a
directory listing of every web server at
a company I would be able to show them
so many vulnerabilities and it's
actually and that's actually not that
hard for the companies to do and no
one's ever taken me up on it but I think
it' be
really best part of acing when you can
just you know critical things
yeah
[Music]
dude all righty critical thinking
Community the time the much awaited time
has come where we announce who the next
co-host is who's going to be my uh my
partner in crime on this podcast and as
you may have guessed it is none other
than reso himself so dude I'm so excited
to have you on the team thank you so
much for taking the position and um I
guess I just wanted to give you a little
bit of a platform now to talk about um
you know why you're such a great fit for
this role um as the co-host and also you
know you're going full-time BG bounty in
like what seven days or something so
just talk about you know that plan and
that
transition yeah when this podcast comes
out it will have been yesterday so I
went fulltime yesterday to the
listeners no yeah I appreciate it I mean
I think that uh it's it's a good fit for
me because I'm a massive fan of cdbb and
I think that uh it's another good fit
because like you said I'm going fulltime
bug Bounty I've been passionate about it
for five or six years trying to go but
work kept reeling me back in and so now
it's it's the right time for me and it's
also you know a potentially a great time
for uh critical thinking um yeah to I
guess the to the platforms uh send me
all your invites and the live hacking
invites to the events uh but no in
general um if if listeners do want to
reach out um super open to collaboration
super open to to learning or to
mentoring you know like just reach out
to me and and chat with me I'll be
active in the critical thinking Discord
so yeah I'm I'm excited to have another
full-time Hunter you know as the co-host
as well because it it's a different
world I think when you're in it all day
every day um and uh so I'm I'm excited
to have you there um you know we we met
at the live hacking events um can you
tell the listenership a little bit about
your journey from uh you know where you
started in bug Bounty and how you ended
up at the live hacking events where we
met and how we landed where we are today
yeah yeah credibility is a huge thing I
want the listeners to know that uh I'm
in the trench with them and have been
dealing with the dupes dealing with the
na and the informationals for a long
time now so yeah uh when I initially got
started honestly I was listening to or I
was seeing like tweets and stuff from
doggy G and nahamsec people like that
and I was like man this feels like it
could be something that's like fun and
lucrative and career building and I
honestly think that you know that'd be
my pitch to people who are listening
that aren't doing bug Bounty yet it's
like even if you make no money you're
building an awesome skill set you're
having a ton of fun you're basically in
my opinion getting like the privilege of
doing something that people in the past
risk their skin for right like people
had to go to J like were like scared
they would go to jail because they would
be hacking things but it was just like
such an intense passion in them and like
a curiosity that they wanted to Sate and
now you can actually um kind of quench
that that desire and get paid to do it
so I think that's really cool but when I
first got started um I was like I'm in
security I was doing blue team stuff and
I was like I already know how to write
code so I feel like I have like two kind
of small advantages there and I want to
Pivot that into into like being F like
acquiring bug Bounty skill and profit
like kind of quicker so I uh you know I
would like hack along with Ben when he
was doing those like live streams he
would do like the live Recon streams and
stuff and dude so many amazing hackers
came out of those live streams really
Ben Ben is what a what an amazing
service to the community he does with
his uh with his live streams and his
hack along alongs yeah yeah we we should
we should do some of those sometime but
yeah um but yeah kind of there quickly
thereafter I found some good
vulnerabilities I knew that I would need
an edge at the beginning when I was
lacking the skill so I would try to go
after brand new targets and so I did
that through new public launches and
then through like you know my first few
private invites which you know I valued
so highly I would get it and just like
drop everything and Sprint to it um my
first live event was actually the Yahoo
uh open scope the kind of open to anyone
which was perfect for me because i' had
never been invited to one right so there
was there was like 3,000 people that
hacked in it
um I was fortunate enough to get an
early invite to the bug Bonnie form
slack which you know some listeners will
definitely know about and um and had
partnered up with Douglas day
Husain uhh Jesse Hogarth and then Eric
um with c c can care of course today is
new and we ended up winning best team in
that event uh across every round and so
it was highly beneficial dude dang that
is that is quite a team I have to say I
understand why that why that turned out
the way that it did yeah and what's
crazy is I was a little worried about
pulling my weight but in the first round
my fuzzing and automation found a sick
crit that like resulted in like a plea
stop bonus if anybody knows what that is
from Yahoo back in the day and it was
like it paid out like 18,000 I think but
um it was really cool because it was a
uh web. ZIP in like another directory
but it was it was hosted on their
infrastructure where it was only Landing
one in 12 times so once I found it I was
like how did no one find this so then I
keping it cheing it there was round
there was only one proxy that it would
actually like let you download the
content from and so anyways that was
just like a dream come true and then of
course once I think once we um got best
team in that it guaranteed another
invite and then you know I was like I've
been on a lot of uh Douglas day AR the
archangels uh you know collaboration
teams um Through The Years through the
through the events and so that
snowballed into some other invites and
so yeah I think I'm at like 11,000
reputation points but um my my last 90
days looks pretty pitiful um been
hacking on Google and then trying to
wrap up stuff at the job so I'm excited
to get the stats stats pumping again I I
know I know you've been doing a great
job with the Google stuff too I've been
kind of poking at them the past couple
days and I'm I'm going to be going going
ham now for the next week um on them and
the scope that they have is really
interesting the the changes they've made
to their program are really attractive
too so I definitely see them being one
of my main Targets in in uh in 2025 if I
can if I can just like I got to break
through that that mentality because I
found a couple bugs on Google before but
like like Google is just such an
intimidating Target right it's just it
and all stuff like if you really think
about it though gcp is so similar to AWS
and people spend like their whole life
hacking AWS and and succeeding you know
so I this isn't an our docket but I did
want to talk to you about this specific
thing now that you bring it up because I
was thinking about this in the shower
actually I know you're a uh a good a
good idea in the shower boy yourself but
hot water what is it about hot water
that makes us have Amazing Ideas yeah I
don't I think it's just the only time
our brain gets the rest because we like
shove stuff in front of our face all the
all the rest of the time but uh what was
Dawning on me was like there are
definitely different
applications which are more fun and less
fun to hack and actually the kind of off
you skated uh you know nature of Proto
buff actually does make it a less
enjoyable experience like I was just
thinking on the spectrum of like what's
fun to hack what's not and I think that
like if a company does have like more
ausc or more whatever less people hack
on of course and that makes it a good
Target from a bug binding perspective
but I was just thinking about how that's
kind of interesting and I want to shift
my mind in that regard too it's like
just because it doesn't feel that
enjoyable immediately how could I make
it enjoyable whether I write a Plugin or
whether I use AI automation to like kind
of reverse the Proto buff or maybe I
think about it in a different way or I
look for a different type of bugs it's
kind of interesting yeah 100 perc I mean
and and that that lack of fun you know
when you're first looking at it that
that additional friction there makes
your competition much less too that's
one of the reasons why I've been excited
to kind of work on Google stuff is like
I know that if I can crack the egg then
it's going to be really really
profitable especially with their
increased bounties they've got recently
so um I think that's that's pretty solid
um and and actually I was a little bit
surprised when you when you said that
that pathway um you know with with the
team that you had on the Yahoo event and
how your automation found stuff because
I didn't really have you in my head as a
as as much of an automation guy like are
you are you looking to kind of dip back
into the automation realm as you go
full-time Hunter are you going to focus
more on manual stuff or you know where
do you kind of put yourself on the
manual to Recon hacker yeah fantastic
question I would say um my my inroad was
definitely automation like I I followed
um
hax's uh oh what's it called how how to
how to shot web or like uh bug bunny
Hunters methodology yes the bug M
Hunters methodology I think it was
version two when I was getting big so
version one was already down I basically
built that exact Pipeline on a random
VPS on digital ocean and use that for a
long time and I would say the vast
majority like over 50% of my bugs for
the first probably three years came from
big fuzzing and from that that that type
of automation um you know when a new
program spun up I would definitely go in
and just immediately look for ey doors
and all that regular stuff but my bread
and butter that I would come back to
every night like everyone go to sleep in
the house and I would hack for two hours
it would be like always fuzzing and uh
you know initially it was like dur
Buster or something like that but very
quickly it became
ffuf um I would I would I would venture
to bet that I've sent more requests on
ffuf than point you know 99.9% of of all
bug buy Hunters that's crazy I have
famously been warned for uh dossing in
like three or four different live
hacking events so sorry sorry about that
I like to spin up fleets of um axum host
and then kind of fuzz from there um yeah
I don't know I think that if if someone
could give me it just feels like panning
for gold right it's like if someone
could give me a directory list in of
every web server at a company I would be
able to show them so many
vulnerabilities and it's actually and
that's actually not that hard for
companies to do and no one's ever taken
me up on it but I think it' be really
interesting just to that's a really
interesting concept yeah yeah it it's
not necessarily as simple with that as
that with modern architectures because
it's not like we're not we're not
dealing with as much of like we talked
about this on an episode like art of the
architectures uh way back there but um
you know we talked about how there's
sort of more like this flat file
architecture where you've got like uh
this is more something you see more in
like a PHP sort of environment where
you've got a you're exposing a file
system to the web via web server right
but then now you know what's becoming
more popular is like these single page
applications backed by apis and stuff
like that um but I mean you're right
even if a companies would just give you
give the the um directory listings for
you know these sort of flat file based
um architectures that they have that
would be I mean you would just because
all that stuff's out there anyway it's
just security by obscurity right um and
lot of times even in the new
architectures they'll still like Mount
full folders oh yeah so like so like
it'll still be at a specific path yeah
exactly um so anyways that was the
initial part of my journey I would say
the last two years it's been a little
bit more manual you know a lot of AI
hacking um but then a lot more manual
testing I think that basically I I
haven't really used my server I like I I
got it spun back up in the last two
months because obviously I'm about to go
full-time and I want to do a lot more
Recon in that regard but before that I
would say for the last two years it's
been a lot more manual hunting manual
hacking um and then that's also during
the time when I transitioned from burp
to kaido because you know I'm not using
the necessarily the scanner the active
scanner as much so yeah yeah yeah wow
okay that that all makes sense I mean I
I've seen you at the live hacking events
and stuff but I hadn't had you sort of
categorized in either one of those
Arenas but it seems like you kind of
have a similar um approach as nogly
which is like you know there there is
some some automation stuff going on but
like when you need to get down to it you
also get in there and you find the idors
and you find the you know application
Level bugs um Beyond just the Recon
World um yep so that's really cool man
um so you're you're going full-time BG
Bounty uh
yesterday so what's the what's the plan
for for how you're gonna how you're GNA
do that I mean obviously we we've got
the full-time Hunters Guild which I'm
I'm uh I I know you're going to be an
active participant in um but what's your
plan moving forward on like what kind of
targets you're going to hit how often
you're going to try hack that sort of
thing yeah I think that as far as the
targets go it's still a little bit up in
the air I'm I definitely want to spend
some time on Google like you mentioned
um I plan to actually basically I've
always felt like new scope like
untouched scope is the way to go so this
is maybe giving away my secret a little
early but my goal is going to be to pull
the top um uh like the you know
basically pull all the top programs that
I trust or the other Hunters trust may
maybe out of a list of like 30 or 40 um
get the then get the ones that are
carded then from those do some sort of
Recon that basically tells me hey here
are the assets that have been spun up in
the last three months to kind of narrow
it down to just those and then work my
way through that list so I know the
program's good I know they pay well I
know they pay Street researchers well I
know they have open scope and then I
know that these domains or these
features yeah I might also just look at
change logs for those companies as well
I do that a lot for Google yeah that
that's that's big I think I think that
that's some some uh stuff that I'm going
to be setting up I've already got a
couple of them monitoring right now but
I I think I'm going to try to build that
out this year every Target that I hack
on religiously I'm going to onward into
my change log monitoring or JS file
monitoring to see when changes occur to
um the API endpoints on that specific
app I I I think it's kind of a waste not
to if you're already taking notes you
already have your whole brain in this
app you understand how it works now you
need to um one of the the takeaways that
I had from an episode with Sam BB was
taking notes with code right that's what
I'm going to do here is like take notes
with code uh to to automate you know my
understanding of this app and make sure
that I'm I'm developing that
understanding over time as that app
continues to develop yeah exactly and I
mean like not only can developers
increase bugs at that level because that
these are new changes and new features
um but also I think that as you learn
the app you can see where there's going
to be regressions or whatever else so um
yeah so that's kind of the methodology
for what I'm going to look at and you
know obviously always pivoting to new
invites and just like basically
conventional wisdom and regard um and by
new invites I mean not new to me but
completely new programs um as far as far
as time as far as time spent and I think
this may have been what you were double
clicking on because uh obviously we just
launched shift but um that so that'll
probably be 60 to 70% of my time as
full-time bug Bounty and the other bits
will be obviously recording and
supporting critical thinking but then
outside of that I would love to build
more tools and so shift is the first one
and so I'll be doing you know some
maintenance and updates and features on
that but um I would I would love to
build other kind of AI apps specifically
in the security space so in fact if
people do have ideas I think that um the
current AI models kind of unlock an
entire new class and Suite of tools that
are possible some of those require a lot
more work some of them don't require
very much at all you just kind of throw
it together and um the ability to
develop so fast now with things like
cursor as I know you've mentioned many
times unel makes it so possible so yeah
lots of building too the um the the
shift thing like I I've been amazed at
how active you've been in that man I
could say like you know we launched this
thing and then guys like every person
that subscribes I see reso like just
sending out an email being like Hey how
do you like the product what do you
think you know give me ideas it's
customer retention come on J dude you're
you're rocking it man and really you
know for anybody who's who's um
subscribing to it right now and getting
access to it uh we're really interested
in in you know your use cases that
aren't being fulfilled or um you know
anything any future progression we
definitely want to hear about that and
actually I was kind of thinking about
this I had it in the notes to talk about
on this episode um you know I've been
working on this program recently where
we have API specs um and they're just
sort of uh free form in like a like a
CSV or whatever and I was like ah man
how cool would it be to like in in sort
of like a cursor like fashion just say
like hey here's this document that
contains API specs here's what I want
you to do with this with this row do you
know this column do this you know set
this to the host you know generate this
token you know put it here you know that
sort of thing and then just have shift
sort of automatedly parse out this API
spec and then create it into a
collection in kaido where you know each
one of the requests is built out fully
and and I think you know we can sort of
do that lower scale right now with with
shift you could pce in like one or two
lines of the that spec and it will
actually create them and stick them in
in replay but I think being able to
upload a full document and then break it
out into certain sections and then like
create the requests for those as as it
goes along as it parses through the
whole document would be another really
cool feature we could integrate yeah
yeah that's a cool idea I think that um
it's probably already possible with a
with a few changes uh so I like it as an
idea and I like that it basically would
give you then a list of um tabs to go
through in replay where it's like I'll
test this one then I'll test this one
then I'll test this one and it's every
end point yep yeah the the crazy thing
that one one of the craziest things
about AI that I really just haven't like
put into words before is how much it
enables you to deal with free form stuff
you know like you never know what format
you're going to get documentation in it
could be a big word doc could be in CSV
could be in like Swagger files could be
in this but if you can just tell the AI
hey this is what it looks like this is
where the information you need is you
know then you can really easily get that
from a format from any format from you
know free form format
into a format that you can ingest and
then put into a tool um and that that
sort of thing is just not possible
without AI without it smartly
identifying yeah I don't currently have
automation that like takes bug Bounty
scope and then like transforms it into
something that my automation uses or
needs but that's a great that's a great
place where that would exist like as I'm
sure you know anybody who tries to do
that programmatically realizes that the
the scope Fields across the different
platforms are different and wild cards
will sometimes look different or
sometimes they'll put it in the
description or whatever but what's
interesting is a a could definitely
abstract that out if you had it like set
up with a specific schema that you
wanted so gez man this is another reason
I'm really excited to have you on the
Pod is it's really great to have a local
AI expert um in sort of be able to talk
about um how to take these these
applications of AI stuff and and apply
it to security and I know that that's
like your [__] so um yeah yeah so I mean
I guess I can pre-apologize and pre-prep
the listener that uh I'm sure I'll bring
lots of AI content just even prepping
for this episode as as me Justin and I
were coming up with resources I had to
kind of like control myself because I
just wanted to keep putting in more AI
stuff in there so uh yeah I think it'll
help Usher the listeners into a world
where they're using Ai and integrating
into their lives earlier than their
peers which is going to give them a huge
level up but I also think that they'll
understand the way AI applications are
being built and that's going to give
them a huge leg up in actually hacking
these applications later yeah dude
massive massive value add there and I
think I I'll always you know bring a
bunch of web stuff as I do you know so I
I think it's great to have a
counterbalance there of like all right
here's some AI here's some tooling um
and then also the web stuff I mean
you've got web stuff in your list right
here too so um yeah I'm dude I'm excited
man this is gonna be awesome thank you
so much for joining the team no thank
you so much thanks thanks for selecting
me slash uh bringing me on as the
co-host it's it's a real pleasure and
honor and I do not take it for granted
so thank you awesome all right well um
trying to think if I had anything else
that I wanted to run by you before we
just kind of jump into the content for
this episode um yeah I think that's a
good I think that's a good intro man if
the if the listeners don't know who you
are at this point you know you guys can
find him on on on Twitter if you want to
read more he's uh he's pretty big on
Twitter you're like what 50 something
thousand followers so yeah I think
almost 55 but um honestly I've been
hearing from people who in the social
media realm that it's like almost uh
that it can be a hindrance because like
if you have like a split audience that
the low engagement rate ratio to your
followers can be whatever but it doesn't
matter yeah I definitely post a ton of
stuff Ai and Bug Bounty so I'm on
Twitter at
resore um which by the way if we have
any listeners from Twitter there's no
one using rezz the account so hook a boy
up sometime I want it and it's unused
and you can't register for character uh
usernames anymore so no oh really oh you
can't yeah so I can't go steal it but
and then I also blog a lot so uh you all
can check out joseph.com yeah yeah the
um the uh newsletter is great too so I
love your writing style of the
newsletter um so cool stuff there all
right well let's let's go into the the
content for this week um we already
talked a little bit about shift and like
how I think that can be really uh useful
for um grabbing free form API docs and
kind of getting them integrated into
your request and your replay um in kaido
um but there was a cool piece of
research that comes out and er that came
out and I just every single time um paos
Yello uh releases something it's it's
very um it's very like outside of the
box you know thinking weaponizing some
things that a lot of people take for
gritted um and and so I I follow I
follow their research pretty closely um
and this time uh they released an
article called double clickjacking a new
era of UI redressing and I've also seen
some research uh it might come out
through the the critical research lab
soon um that just also really really
weaponized as well
um pages that can be framed so like
previously I wouldn't really consider
x-frame options header missing as like a
like a like a mega Gadget yeah but um
after seeing this and after seeing some
of the research from the lab um there is
a lot of stuff you could do um if you
have x no xrem options header and same
site uh uh cookies are are not an issue
um and the way that this specific
research sort of addresses this scenario
is it invites a user to doubleclick on
something and with the first click the
mouse down event it it um it harvests
that to close a window and then you know
the mouse up event happens and when the
mouse down event happens again the
user's uh cursor right where it was on
that button will be aligned over a uh
sort of popped under page that was done
in preparation for this attack and can
Harvest a single click on a button on a
uh sensitive page and um I was like okay
you know that's kind of kind of crafty
kind of cool you know and then I I went
and looked at these um these uh demo
videos that they recorded for Salesforce
slack Shopify and one-click account
takeovers and they're pretty freaking
good dude double click I can't take
overs yeah double click exactly double
click on on on the platforms it's one
but then the the vulnerability is also
one yeah so right right but you mean
technically yeah I guess it's a two
click you know because you're going D
but um you know you go on there you you
click the capture especially excuse me
especially with captas and uh except
cookies stuff priming users to just give
a click without a second thought um I
think this will result in some very
impactful stuff if done correctly um I'm
not I'm not sure I would report this as
is but uh maybe change with something
else like the oath low um I think it's I
think it's worthwhile I think it's a
valid bug yeah so uh before we jump to
kind of the really cool kind of
mitigations here uh which are really
neat so you all definitely want to
listen to that I just wanted to say
clickjacking in general I definitely
have always kind of like you know like
you said look down my nose at from a bug
bounty hunting perspective but I don't
but I think that yeah I think it I'm
underrating it a little bit I remember
Jesse uh hogar 45 back like three years
ago showed me an amazing clickjacking uh
vulnerability that resulted in like a
account takeover and then recently in
the Google event in Malaga Spain this
fall or I guess back in November
somebody had a really neat clickjacking
demo that it was like based around Gmail
so I don't know I don't I don't know all
the details and I don't know if I could
share them anyways because I think we
were under NDA but um but there was a
vulnerability that paid out that was
like extremely impactful that uh did
some clickjacking and some like uh kind
of user trickery where like it had the
user play a little game for the capture
that resulted in extremely lot like a
severe impact so it's worth uh it's
worth considering this this blog is just
well written and the poc's like you said
are are money do you want to talk about
these really cool mitigation things he
brought up yeah yeah so um definitely
the mitigation things are we'll get to
those in just a second but I just want
to Echo that like the the crazy thing
about clickjacking is I think it gets a
bad rap
because like people will report it
without proving impact right but just
think about this for a second you know
in the oath scenarios that they're
talking about there where you're proving
an oo application with one click that
can you know do anything to your account
that's the highest amount of impact you
can achieve on the client side right if
you if you have a you know one-click
account takeover that is the highest
amount of impact you can achieve on the
client side period right so if you if
you are in in a clickjacking scenario
where you come to the attacker's page
you click one button on that page right
that is like one and your account gets
poned that is like one click away from
the highest impact uh scenario that you
can run into on the client side so I
mean it's really this is one of the
classes where it's really about
weaponization and if you can take it and
take it the full the full Mile and uh
and and get the account takeover out of
it or get you know maybe if you can one
click delete your account or you know
one click do some other um very
sensitive action uh then I think that
will often result in in some accepted
bug yeah and isn't reflected xss
basically the same thing like it's still
a oneclick kind of account take over the
thing with r xss is you can like spray
it because you can kind of put that
payload anywhere whereas I think a lot
of clickjacking you have to get them on
your page but in general it's kind of
the same right you just spray the link
to your safe looking page that is
malicious that has the the framed page
on it and so it still looks legitimate
and so yeah I think they're very similar
like you said clickjacking as like a as
like a phrase may be kind of um frowned
upon but in general if you still have a
weaponized payload it should probably it
should probably be taken seriously so
yeah for sure okay what is this uh what
are these protections for the double
click tracking stuff that they had here
yeah I think I was pointing this out to
you when we were talking about it before
the before the Pod it's just like it's
so neat that um there's both a
JavaScript based protection here
mitigation that anyone can Implement on
these on these super sensitive Pages
where a single click has like a lot of
impact and then and then um they also go
into the details for how browsers could
completely fix this which I think which
I think you thought was neat uh how that
actually would would be implemented yeah
no this is this is great uh I think
there should be some addressing of this
at the at the browser level but I mean
especially for those programs that want
to be very thorough with they're like
with the places in their application
where one click can take over your
account right because that's a pretty
stringent scenario already and pretty
much the only only place you kind of see
this is is an oath authorization um uh
and and so if you just add this one
little snippet of JavaScript which um
you know removes the the risk of double
clickjacking by disabling critical
buttons uh unless a gesture is detected
um then you you know you you save
yourself from this sort of attack even
if you have to allow the page to be um
uh framed uh which which and actually in
this scenario it's it's not even framing
because they're they're popping it up in
in a lot of a lot of ways so um there's
there's a bunch of um scenarios where
this can be exploited exploited further
but just being able to add that one
little snippet into your page to make
sure that there's some movement of the
mouse that sort of thing before that
button becomes enabled I think it's
something that should be added to those
high high value ooth Pages where it can
result in in oneclick ATO because you
those pages need special security
concern anyway so this is just one extra
step yeah it does it reminds me of the
vulnerabilities you found with CSS
injection and on those credit card Pages
it's like when there's a highly
sensitive page things that might not
typically be vulnerabilities can kind of
become those and honestly another really
key point about this blog is that like
he gives you the mitigation and I think
I think having mitigation in bug Bounty
reports is one of the best ways to get
them accepted and to also get those kind
of like well-written report bonuses and
stuff and it makes it makes teams take
you seriously it's like hey here's a
vulnerability and here's how you fix it
right now you just put this JavaScript
on the page and it removes this and I
think it really showcases the fact that
there is a vulnerability and that there
is a single fix in that single place
yeah yeah for sure and and dude I I
gotta you got to remind me as we record
future episodes um the our editor has
said that I really should be sharing my
screen when I'm talking about these
articles so we can get it up on YouTube
sorry sorry folks on trind you I I
always forget to do that but I just want
did want to add one more thing as we as
we move away from this subject which is
that um just want to quote specifically
from the article here it says um double
click jacking adds a layer uh many
defenses were never designed to handle
methods like x-frame options same site
cookies and CSP cannot defend against
this attack so I know we sort of covered
clickjacking as a as a specific um
attack you know while we were talking
about double clickjacking but double
click jacking is very different because
it uses uh like popup windows and stuff
like that um and so you know it's going
to be a top level navigation so same
cookies pass all your cookies it's a
it's a completely legitimate click on
the under on the under page yeah there's
no protection for that part yeah there's
there's nothing you can do with that um
and it doesn't have anything to do with
framing either so it's not going to
happen and and um you know a lot of
these
modern-day attacks that utilize uh
different windows and Frames um will uh
be stopped by Coupe um which is um cross
origin I forget the actual let me let me
look up the actual acronym
um cross origin opener policy yeah
that's it um which you know removes that
opener relationship um but this one I
think could also be implemented without
even though Coupe was in place so
there's lots of uh ways that this attack
sort of bypasses traditional attack
mechanisms um uh so just wanted to make
sure that was clear and we weren't
getting confused with clickjacking and
and uh the prerequisites for that attack
y um all right so yeah we're worth test
worth testing in places where those
protections still exist because they are
still vulnerable most I think you kind
of have to feel out the teams as well
because some teams are going to be like
yeah well you know what are do you know
but um if you're working with teams that
are high quality and the PC is really
clean then it could get accepted or it
could not get accepted you know and
that's just kind of the risk you take
with these sort of Fringe attacks that
require a little bit more user
interaction yeah they say in here that
the that the uh results were mixed but
this but he says most have chosen to
address it while some have chosen not to
so honestly I I would have expected the
opposite but I I would not surprise me
if the mitigation being a part of the
report is one reason why they were like
yeah we'll just accept this and throw
this mitigation on the page right so
yeah that's great um Okay cool so that
was the double clickjacking one um you
want to hop down to Expo stuff sure yeah
so um I actually am adviser at ethc uh
which is the um one of the kind of
automated hacking platforms out of
Portugal started by our boy Andre oxac
shout out to our Boro X ACB yeah he's
the man and so as a part of that you
know um they may or may not be working
on hackbot uh but uh in my research for
that and and in my support of that um I
yeah shared with them this validation
Benchmark it's actually two top bug
Hunters Dorado and do you know who the
other person is yeah nean right yeah
yeah nean are both on the Expo team and
so Expo is building a hackbot it is yeah
it's it's I'm yeah it's amazing and the
the founders are also like really
brilliant but um so anyways this link
will be in the show notes but if you if
you wanted to search for it yourself if
you just look up Expo engineering
validation benchmarks they have Man O
over 100 benchmarks which are really
cool they include like uh like a Docker
compos file that will help you spin up a
little app that has a single
vulnerability that you can then um um
test your AI system at hacking so like
let's say that you're a Bug Hunter and
you want to start implementing AI to be
able to solve your xss or your idore or
whatever just just to play with it
either to learn it or because legit it
could pay off and make you money this is
like a perfect place to go to test those
um systems against little micro exploits
where they're very vulnerable these are
not like hard things to solve for the
majority of them and I think they
increase in difficulty but wow yeah so
this these this is sort of a this
benchmarking is a lot of work you know
putting together all of these GitHub
repos and and or or Docker uh containers
and stuff like that and uh they've kind
of done that leg work and then released
it for the community so that they can um
so that people can use these to make
sure their hack Bots are are achieving
the goal um and and I think that's
really cool because a lot of times when
I'm building automation I need a a test
case you know a vulnerable test case
right and uh often times I train him off
the actual vulnerabilities that I find
manually um but if you have those on
hand or if you'd like to you know train
it on what you found manually and then
sort of apply it to a benchmark and say
hey does it but does it figure out this
scenario um this is a great way to to
validate that um and and I guess do they
have it um broken out into like what
specific types of bugs are each one of
yeah they don't they they don't have the
top level but if you click into them
they definitely do so yeah uh actually I
don't know the the titles even when you
click in are not oh yeah so
vulnerability type and category yeah
it's in the read me yeah yeah so So like
idore um broken oh and also difficulty
too I hadn't noticed that there's a
difficulty field so you could even like
you know cherry pick the easy ones or
cherry pick the hard ones or whatever
nice yeah cross- side scripting
injection difficulty hard interesting
cool yeah so these will definitely be
helpful for anybody who's building a
hackbot um which I think there are more
and more researchers uh yeah in the
fulltime Hunters Guild I won't Le their
name but one of the fulltime Hunters has
already found a high vulnerability with
their own personal hackbot that they
train themselves to WR in like a week so
yeah dude we they a talented developer
so yeah we got we we got to definitely
make sure we're staying on top of uh of
all that I think it's going to be
helpful to have one of those on your
team uh as as you keep moving forward um
okay any any other comments on that one
or is that that one do that no I was
gonna ask you about this jorian tweet
yeah okay get some water my throat is a
little scratchy today um yeah so uh
obviously you know let let me just say
what I say all the time when Gareth
Hayes tweets anything you should pay
attention to that tweet um and Garett
tweeted out on Christmas Eve uh and
we're just getting the chance to cover
it now that uh he found that you can use
ISO uh 2022 JP um charet Escape
sequences inside of JS URLs so uh this
is going to break a lot of uh uh wafts
and hardcoded uh like scenarios where
they're just just looking for JavaScript
colon right if they had like a hardcoded
no Javas script colon um you know taking
in in some accommodations for HTML
encoding and stuff like that um then
that's very hard to bypass when you're
trying to to do a a um a URL or like an
HF based attack um but this this
scenario that he outlines here allows
you to do a payload and I will share my
screen on this one now so people can
people can actually see the Tweet um
yeah in this in this scenario he
outlines uh a way to actually get it to
pop with uh bunch of whack characters in
there um so this and then there was
another comment so this is where jorian
comes in a little bit further down on
Twitter um where he says hey uh Gareth
was saying hey this doesn't work on
Chrome and joran noticed that if you
just Spam the uh the escape sequence for
this uh specific character set a bunch
of times then Chrome successfully sniffs
it if there's no character set defined
on that page and will actually trigger
it even though it doesn't work right off
the bat like it does in Firefox so um
this works in both Firefox and chrome if
there's no character set defined that
you can send in this payload like Java s
space you know uh escape sequence thing
um script colon alert one um and it will
actually trigger that in the browser um
and they provided some example links on
how this might work in that Twitter
thread so we'll have those Linked In the
description but um been amazing no did
you reply yeah yeah so in in in our dock
here click click on my link there's no
spam and it still pops so I don't know
if um if it's just my browser locally
that's behaving that way or if jorian
was um Incorrect and just figured out a
different way to make it pop but
basically I was like that spam doesn't
feel that necessary so I went and
started removing some of those
characters and it it totally pops for me
in Chrome if you remove a bunch of them
so maybe maybe more research required
there yeah so I think you still have one
of the one or two of the Escape
sequences so maybe you don't need to do
that many uh but there's like a smaller
amount of Escape sequences that you can
use and create a more Consolidated
payload nice I like that yeah we'll um
we'll drop that down in the description
as well Richard um if the one that's
highlighted in the doc uh if you could
add that to the description that would
be great um Okay cool so yeah I just
want I I kind of want to keep the
community up to date on this these sort
of uh character set related attacks that
have been kind of popping up a ton
lately it's perfect for w bypasses and
other things yeah yeah it it's it's
great for those scenarios and I think
it's a little bit less common that the
character set isn't defined but just
like scenarios that we were just talking
about where you know um xrem options
headers might be missing uh this is
stuff that we weren't really paying
attention to as much before but like now
I think should start really being like
ah this is a gadget you know if there's
no character set defined this is a
gadget if there's some ability to inject
any text in the P um which is a pretty
low bar to me right in my opinion so
yeah did I don't I know I'm sure that
you probably already geeked out about
this but what's funny about this
character set specifically is it's for
like a Japanese email it's like a 2022
Japanese code Point email thing and it's
yeah it's hilarious yeah dude I love I
love it when my my interests overlap
like that um uh when you've got some
stuff that's only available in Japanese
I love it when um uh kinal masato
released some stuff in Japanese first
and I get to go like read it and be like
he he he
like I understand this and then he does
the English release like a day later and
I'm like [__] but but um I do love it
when there's there's that aspect um so
speaking of gare
haes yeah yeah dude so you you dropped
to this one this SVG related tweet in
here as well right yeah yeah so um
obviously SVG xss has been around a
little while um and I do uh know and
remember your rule about always paying
attention to gareth's tweet so actually
wanted to I wanted to ask you why
specifically and Justin would not answer
this offline everyone because we thought
it would be great contact for the
podcast what is special about this uh
payload that made him you know tweet and
share it yeah so um the the payload that
Gareth shared is a SVG xss payload um
and like you said you know it's pretty
common knowledge that we can get xss
from svgs uh if the content type is uh
image xvg plus XML um and then it's
being loaded up in in a frame in the
browser right it doesn't work from an
image tag um which is a common
misconception um but what Gareth tweeted
out here that's a little bit special is
that uh you can actually use HT or um
XML entities to sort of prime this
attack uh which may help bypass some uh
wafts that are blocking your your
malicious uh SVG payload or it it can
also help in the scenario where the your
SVG is being sanitized um when it's
being uploaded because there are some
SVG softwares that will look and say
okay you know is there an a hre item in
here that um is being dynamically
generated or is there a script tag
that's being D you know that's being
created when I'm create uh uploading
this SVG file and then stripping it out
so it's non-malicious
um Gareth is highlighting here that you
can actually use uh XML entities which
is something we normally just associate
with server side attacks um for xxe to
actually craft a malicious SVG um that
actually only becomes malicious at
runtime when the the XML is pared by the
browser um yeah that's interesting like
you said th even if you stripped out any
script tags this would still make it
through that W or make it through that
sanitization so yeah 100% so this is
another one that's that's kind of
interesting to keep in your in your
pocket um and I just want to shoot out a
reminder because there's a there was a a
couple you know higher level hackers
recently that I was talking to that seem
to be under the the concept uh that you
could get SV xss from an SVG um that was
loaded into an image tag and you know
I'm happy to be proven wrong but I've
never seen that work uh it's just when
the browser is parsing or parsing the
SVG in in the frame directly so you
navigate directly to that SVG um uh that
that that payload will actually pop and
that's because the browser is parsing
XML as as well with that with that SVG
not just considering it to be an image
right so yeah that's that's a a cool
shout out as well there from Gareth
um dude my throat is dying man it's you
know it's winter here it's been snowing
this whole week and my everything is
just so dry it's you got snow as well
right yeah we got I mean I'm sure that
this is true all across the US
especially across the Midwest we're
getting more snow than we've basically
ever gotten um we got like eight inches
here in Kentucky and dude no way like
yeah and three to six are coming in the
next two days um so I'm enjoying the
cold plunge my wife got me for Christmas
the cold plunge oh my gosh that's got to
be legendary yeah we got like in here in
in Virginia um but we've had we've had
worse before so the kids are having fun
with it though for sure nice well I mean
your throat will make it through the
next two I think right we've only got
two left yeah yeah so let me let me jump
back over I'm gonna just do one quick
shout out um uh to a project called curl
D
cffi um this so many of you as you're
building automation um will run into
scenario where uh these these sites are
running Cloud flare and they will not
like your TLS um handshake that you do
from like python requests or something
like that um someone created this
awesome project in in Python called C-
cffi which essentially allows you to
impersonate uh Chrome's TLS uh signature
or fingerprint and use it in Python and
you can just literally import from it
like import from uh curl cffi as
requests and then just use it like you
normally would in request so you're
obsessed with these matrixes make sure
you share your screen and show the
Matrix of the support on there okay all
right hold on let me let me do it
because Justin himself is a big fan of
these uh of these uh matrixes love and
then on top of that this this uh tool is
really cool so yeah this is great so
this is the this is the tool right here
curl cffi um and it's super easy to
integrate um into the project you can
literally I I'm showing it on the screen
now but um you can just from curl _ cffi
import requests and then use requests
just exactly like you would uh as as
your primary you know HTTP interfase in
Python so and it allows you to
impersonate Chrome um super super simply
which has allowed me to get around a
bunch of uh cloudflare related stuff um
so I wanted to just shout that out there
for anybody who might be dealing with
similar issues there um and then I'll
jump right into this CS cspt um yeah
thing if that's cool with you before my
voice gives out um so we're recording
this on the 9th and this was released
this morning so uh sorry guys if I
haven't if I don't do it full Justice to
the homies over there at uh doy Inc but
um they've been doing some really
awesome work on one of my favorite bug
bug types uh client side path traval and
we've done a bunch of um master classes
and stuff like this uh on this on this
actual vulnerability type in the the
Discord so check those out if you're
interested um but the research that came
out was essentially how to to use a uh
one of the ways to exploit cspt because
cspt by itself is not a vulnerability
it's a gadget and that Gadget has to be
weaponized with another Gadget um and
one of the most common ways to do that
there's like open redirect um there's
like response poisoning or whatever um
and then one of the most common ones is
to get a file uploaded onto the server
that has like a Json in it and then get
the cspt to Traverse hit that Json file
the the JavaScript that triggered that
that fetch request or whatever will
parse that Json and use your malicious
values um and integrate them into the
Dom and cause xss or some bad um uh you
know effect on the application um so
what the people over at Doc did was a
little bit of research on how to get
fetch to process Json uh effectively and
and with different file types and the
one the one that they released here was
uh PDF um and and how a lot of the
libraries for uploading PDFs will use
very liberal checking of the magic bytes
at the beginning of the file and what
was it like in the first yeah in the
first like 1,2 uh 1,24 characters if
there is% PDF then it will bypass the
PDF upload um and the PDF uploader will
still think this is a PDF and you can
actually integrate just normal Json um
into that that file which can then be
processed by uh by the um csbt so uh
they they provided a couple different um
libraries PDF lib um and what was the
other one uh file file type within a
specific um Li uh language I can't find
the other one here but there's a couple
um libraries that were vulnerable to
this mm magic and then PDF PDF lib and
then that one you just mentioned yeah
the crazy thing is like to me this is
really cool because I'm always thinking
about you know the highest impact
possible and I love that file uploads
are so frequently uh considered rce you
know this with um in this case it may or
may not be I didn't have a chance like
you said you sent me this this morning I
didn't get to read it all but just of
you that's fine in general file uploads
are often rce right and so like
understanding the way that the backend
server is deciding whether or not a file
type is allowed was really cool to me
like when I was reading that I was like
oh wow this is amazing like not only can
I potentially trick the um content type
you know header or directive there but
then you can also you know like I've
known about magic bites and how to
potentially modify those but it's it's
it's a really um cool idea that and I
guess it's more just a cool
vulnerability yeah that some of these
libraries do something as simple as look
for the magic bite of you know percent
PDF or whatever within the first
thousand bytes so well that's a great
point I mean this is this research is
cross applicable in lots of areas right
if there's very permissive um parsing of
this file type then you might end up
being able to get files on the server
that uh are more or that contain
malicious content easier um so and
normally when I think about the magic
bites right I I'm thinking oh these have
to be um defined at the very beginning
of the first bite yeah um but apparently
there are a lot of uh PDF parsing
engines that will allow it to be
anywhere in the first 1,24 bytes so yeah
this this gives us a lot of flexibility
not only with client side path reversals
but uh which you know would just
normally result in excess ass or some
impact on the client side but also um wi
file upload scenarios like you mentioned
yeah yeah pretty solid uh definitely big
shout out to to their team they've been
really diving deep on the specific
vulnerability type um and I I love to
see the research come out and check that
out dude they shouted metion nice they
did they did and oh yeah that was the
other thing I'm glad I scrolled down to
the bottom to flex on the people about
my shout out in this blog um uh because
they also uh mention this um csbt
playground which is a a get up repo that
they um released that contains a Docker
container and a bunch of little um Labs
that you can do to strengthen your cspt
knowledge uh and guys let me tell you
this gadget is everywhere cspt is
everywhere um massive bug type that is
uh underrated by uh the security
community in general I think
so definitely something you want to kind
of wrap your head around and be able to
exploit uh if you're doing web
application auditing with any
frequency yep there you go all right
what what's the uh what's the last one
you got on your list here AI crash
course yeah so I mean um in general
everyone wants a quick easy hack right
and everyone loves those uh
resource-based gith hubs where it's like
here's a list of all the resources you
need to know about xss and I do think
it's kind of easy to ignore them or not
ever go through them um but if people
are willing to buckle down and really
learn I think that you can learn a lot
of stuff in under two weeks and that's
what this um that's what this link uh is
that got shared let me see if I can
share it really
quickly
share screen oh sweet yeah single Chrome
tab perfect so U this has been going
around in a bunch of the AI engineering
circles um along with a subtext that's
basically like get you know become an AI
engineer in two weeks so supposedly you
could you could take this AI crash
course in in two weeks but it's just a
list of resources if you had to go from
zero understanding to full comprehension
of how current AI engineering Works
basically it it starts with like how the
neural networks like what exactly is an
Earl Network so you can kind of skip
some of the stuff if you want poke
around and then they even highlight with
asteris the most important ones to uh
focus on um but yeah there's a list of
paper yeah there's a list of papers a
list of the major applications some of
the benchmarks and then the video
lecture series you know this is probably
if I were spinning up where I would
spend my time I I don't know why I just
learned really well by watching and then
doing and so I would probably follow
these while building stuff on the side
as I go specifically Andre Andre
karthi's series is great I in general I
don't think that especially the hacker
Community needs to like be training
their own models or doing anything crazy
like that but understanding the power of
these models and understanding how to
plug them um up with like tools and and
hook them up to different capabilities
and functionality is really going to
give you a leg up when it comes to
hacking or building your own uh your
your own like AI tooling or your own you
know AI infrastructure for yourself yeah
so I just wanted to share this with the
community because I thought it was a
really great resource you know pick and
choose click through learn um kind of
fill in some of your gaps if you're
interested in it yeah and and I think
even just understanding the basics of
like linkchain and um and getting all
this stuff in your your normal
development environment in Python or in
node or whatever you're go or whatever
you're writing in um is really really
really helpful because then you can
start using these this tool you know AI
just as another piece of your automation
um uh and yeah I think any any anytime
you you move forward and you utilize AI
you're kind of providing more cushion
for yourself if you're worried at all
about AI really affecting the security
industry because you are now weaponizing
that thing you're going to be the one
that pushes that that industry a little
bit further with your Innovation using
the AI so definitely definitely wild
topic yeah and I don't think we're all
going to be replaced or anything anytime
soon but let's say in five or 10 years
we were to like see actual impact on bug
Bounty from this this type of automation
because Expo pops off or something you
know I think in general kind of getting
up to speed with AI is going to mean
that you will be the cream of the crop
when it comes to companies that are
trying to utilize or build on top of AI
or you know want want to implement or
learn like what are out there so in
general I think it's a really nice hedge
because it's going to level yourself up
while um while increasing your
productivity so yeah I mean Expo was
what 11th in the US that that last year
that was crazy um so definitely
definitely something to keep an eye out
if you know I'm not going to call out
you know our homies uh you know that
work at expo at all um I don't know how
much of that is like expose product
finding bugs and like fully exploiting
them on bug Bounty program um I I
literally honestly just don't know but I
know that it would not be very hard for
the folks that work at at at at Expo get
in the 11th Place in the US like those
guys are some of the most talented
Hunters out there the the the team from
Spain over there um so definitely um
excited to see that though because I
think there is a lot of progress being
made in the industry there yeah yeah
sweet I guess one other thing I was
gonna ask you about as before we close
here was um if there was anything on
your top of mind for the listeners as
they we go into 25 C we just had the
kind of all hands meeting with the CTB
ctbb team was there anything from that
that kind of flowed over that you
thought the listener needed to know yeah
I mean I I think I think just as far as
the direction that ctbb is going in 2025
um you know we're really going to try to
focus on the research lab uh you know
trying to get research from the research
lab and present it on the Pod so it's
going to be original research and I just
sort of reiterated with the whole team
the North Star for critical thinking
which is we want to um deliver you know
high energy motivational very
technically informative content every
week to the community um with the goal
of you know even the most skilled
researchers coming away from each
episode with like oh yeah hadn't really
thought of that or uh you know have one
actionable takeaway that that will
change their methodology as they
approach a Target um and that's kind of
what the North Star has been and I think
will continue to be um throughout
throughout 2025 it is easy to lose track
of that but um I we do have the team
keeping us accountable now you know you
know focusing in on that and and really
um trying to spend more time developing
the the plans for these episodes so that
we can get that technical depth required
to achieve that goal y absolutely I mean
I think that that's been why I've Loved
critical thinking so much and I think
that it is a perfect Northstar right um
because our audience base all of the
listeners all of our friends that we
talk to and hang out with all the time
are such practical people like we all
just want the Practical brass tax advice
let me go impl this so I can you know uh
suceed more make more money um or or
just do something really groundbreaking
and I think um you know we care a lot
about those really cool Noel
breakthroughs um the hacker hacker
culture and hacker subculture has always
been really um has always gotten really
excited about novel breakthroughs new
techniques new strategies and yeah we we
want to bring that to you all dude it's
it's crazy though to see to be in the
this researcher chat with the crit with
the critical thinking research team like
like you know we've got frons we've got
we've got Matan in there we've got Mizu
we've got monkey hacks we've got Haku
piku piku Haku wherever in Discord
versus Twitter but I mean that that team
is really stacked and they really
already just in the like week we've
launched this have bounced off of each
other a lot being like Oh what if we did
this so we could weaponized this this
way um so I really expect to see some
awesome stuff out of them in 2025 and
I'm really gonna be privileged to
distribute that on the podcast I think
yeah and one thing I think I told you in
the All Hands a minute ago and I told
the rest of the team I think that
everything we talk about here is
extremely applicable to people out there
who are web app testing or are pin
testing and I want the leaders of those
or I want the leaders of those
organizations to like be thinking like
oh our employees our hackers have to be
listening to ctbb because that's going
to make them the best version of
themselves that's going to make them the
best hackers on the planet and so yeah
if if if you listen or if you work at a
place where you've got you know friends
who are doing pin testing or are doing
web app testing like definitely refer
the Pod recommend people to check it out
yeah yeah definitely all right man I
think that's a wrap on this episode I'm
going to go get some like snow and like
put it on my throat it's so
raspy sweet dude yeah thanks again um
I'm excited about this year can't wait
to to bring more awesome content to you
all sweet
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb Dosh
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
to master classes amas hack along alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there